The Road to Civilisation is Not Always Civilised.
Meek's Cutoff is a western, drama film directed by Kelly Reichardt.
A group of settlers traveling through the Oregon High Desert in
1845 find themselves stranded in harsh conditions.
Emily Tetherow, played by Michelle Williams.
Stephen Meek, played by Bruce Greenwood.
Soloman Tetherow, played by Will Patton.
Millie Gately, played by Zoe Kazan.
Thomas Gately, played by Paul Dano.
Glory White, played by Shirley Henderson.
Meek's Cutoff is a 2010 American Western historical survival film directed by Kelly Reichardt and starring Michelle Williams,
Bruce Greenwood, Paul Dano, Zoe Kazan, Will Patton, Shirley Henderson, Neal Huff, Tommy Nelson, and Rod Rondeaux.
The story is loosely based on a historical incident on the Oregon Trail in 1845, in which frontier guide Stephen Meek led a wagon train on an
ill-fated journey through the Oregon High Desert along the route later known as the Meek Cutoff in the western United States.
The film was shown in competition at the 67th
Venice International Film Festival.
The film is formatted in the Academy ratio (1.37:1), a
standard used in many classic Westerns.
The film explores themes of immigrant, gold, territory, tree, confidence.
The tone is emotional.